grafolio.com 2019-07-06

# Creator's Playground: Grafolio

_NAVER Corporation_ (hereinafter the "Company") abides by privacy protection regulations in all laws an information communications service provider must abide by, including the Act on Promotion of Information and Communications Network Utilization and Information Protection, Privacy Protection Act, Protection of Communications Secrets Act and the Telecommunications Business Act, and provides a Privacy Policy that is based on related laws and regulations to protect user’s rights and interests.  
This Grafolio Privacy Policy is applied to the use of Grafolio and its relating services provided by the Company, and contains the following information. 

### 1\. Collected personal information and method

#### A. Collected personal information

First, The company supports various SNS logins for convenient member registration and service provision, and during this process processes the following personal information. However, the types and methods of SNS login may vary by country. 

\- Register with Naver ID: Naver ID, nickname, profile picture, email address, age, gender 

\- Register with Facebook: Email address, public profile information (name, profile picture, age, gender) 

\- Register with Weibo: Nickname, profile picture, gender 

\- Email login: Email address, name, user name (URL) 

Second, by user’s choice, profile information (profile image, country, gender, age, website, public email address, area of activity, social media service, history) can be collected. Also, while using the services, IP Address, cookie, date of visit, service usage information, bad usage record, device information, and payment information can be collected. Email address and phone number may be collected while receiving and processing customer inquiry. 

#### B. How personal information is collected

Collect through subscription, member information modification, event participation and through tools for collecting generated information  
Through accepting inquiries in Customer Center via web page, fax and phone 

### 2\. Personal Information Collection and Purpose of Use

#### A. Executing agreements made to provide services, and when settling accounts for the provided services

When providing contents for the use of web sites and mobile service, customized serviced provided by Grafolio and Grafolio-based services (NAVER included), delivering goods or invoices, self-authentication and during purchase and fee payment and collection

#### B. Managing members

When providing subscription services, personal identification, imposing restrictions to members who violate the Grafolio terms of use, restricting actions that interrupt operation of the service and illegal use of the service, confirming the intention to subscribe; restricting subscriptions and number of subscriptions, restoring records for dispute arbitration, handling customer services including complaints, delivering notifications and confirming the intention to unsubscribe.

#### C. Developing new services and use in marketing, advertising activities

When developing new services and providing customized service, providing services based on statistical characteristics and placing advertisements, confirming the validity of the service, providing event information and opportunities to participate, providing advertising information, identifying access frequency, collecting statistics on member’s service usage.

### 3\. Disclosure and Provision of Personal Information

The company must use the user’s personal information within the range specified in "2. Personal Information Collection and Purpose of Use", not exceed the said range without prior consent from the user, and as a principal rule, not disclose users’ information. However, the following is an exception.

A. When requested by an investigative agency, through procedures and methods defined by law, for investigative purposes, in accordance with legal regulations.

### 4\. Entrusting the Handling Personal Information

The following personal information is entrusted to improve the company’s services, and the necessary provisions have been prepared, in accordance with related laws, for the safety of users’ personal information when executing an agreement to entrust personal information.  
Organizations entrusted to handle the company’s personal information and the entrusted tasks are as shown below; 

Entrusting the Handling Personal Information Entrusted Company | Entrusted Tasks | Personal Information Retention and Use Term  
---|---|---  
NAVER Business Platform Corporation | Entrusting system operation for providing service | Until consignment agreement termination or member withdrawal  
NAVER BUSINESS PLATFORM ASIA PACIFIC PTE. LTD | Data Storage  
NIT Service Corporation | Operation of infrastructure  
NAVER I&S Corporation | Purchase and delivery of giveaways for events, Service operation, Customer support.  
inComms Co., Ltd, Greenweb Service., Ltd | Customer support, Service operation  
Danal Co., Ltd., KSNET INC., KG Inicis Co., Ltd., NHN KCP Corp., HYOSUNG FMS INC, LG Uplus Corp., Allat. Corp., KG Mobilians Co., Ltd., Korea Information&Communication Co., Ltd., Settlebank INC, VP Inc, Galaxia Communications Co., Ltd., Credit-card companies (HYUNDAI CARD Corp., LOTTECARD CO., LTD, KB KOOkmin Card Co. LTD., BC Card Co., Samsung Card CO., LTD., Shinhan Card Co., Ltd., KEB Hana Card Co., Citigroup Inc., NH BANK, KWANGJU BANK, JB Bank, JEJUBANK, Suhyup Bank), Shinhan Bank, and all other banks registered for Naver Pay Easy Payment Services account. | Payment processing (Verifying cell phone, payment without a bankbook, bank transfer, credit card, gift certificate, and other means of payment and refund account) and preventing payment embezzlement  
NICE Information Service Co., LTD, Seoul Credit Rating and Information Inc., KGMobilians Co., LTD, and Dreamsecurity Co., LTD. | Identification  
  
_The personal data consignments handled by overseas corporates are as follows._

NAVER will not share personal data of users to any other foreign operators. However, 'NAVER Business Platform Asia Pacific' will handle consignment work for data storage as follows. As affiliate companies, they shall too follow the same Privacy Policy as NAVER and protect the user data accordingly while fulfilling duties adhering to the strict regulations of NAVER.

The personal data consignments handled by overseas corporates Consignment Company | NAVER BUSINESS PLATFORM ASIA PACIFIC PTE. LTD  
---|---  
Location of Consignment Company | Hong Kong (RM 1808. 18/F HARCOURT RD ADMIRALTY HONG KONG)  
Consignment date and way | October 13, 2016  
Remote transmission using private network  
Data management manager's contact info | [nbpcc@naver.com](mailto:nbpcc@naver.com)  
Consignor's personal info field | Matches the data, including personal information collected and stored by NAVER  
Consignment business details | National data backup (storage) for the protection of user data from disasters, catastrophes, etc.  
Privacy Policy and Terms of Use | Matches the retention period outlined in this Privacy Policy  
  
### 5\. Personal Information Retention and Use Term

User’s personal information is discarded immediately after the purpose of its collection and use has been achieved. However, the following information is stored for below purpose over the stated duration.

#### A. If the information is required to be stored according to internal regulations set forth by the Company

**\- Delinquent use record** Storage reason: Prevent delinquent uses  
Storage period: One (1) year 

#### B. If the information is required to be stored according to regulations of related laws

The users’ personal information can be stored for a certain period of time, as is stipulated by related laws, in the event the information is required to be stored according to regulations of related laws, such as commercial law and the Act on the Consumer Protection in the Electronic Commerce Transactions. In such cases, the information will only be used for the stored purpose, over the duration stated below. 

**\- Records of subscription or withdrawal from subscription** Storage reason: Act on the Consumer Protection in the Electronic Commerce Transactions, etc.  
Storage period: Five (5) years 

**\- Records of supplying, such as goods and payment settlements** Storage reason: Act on the Consumer Protection in the Electronic Commerce Transactions, etc.  
Storage period: Five (5) years 

**\- Records of customer complaints or dispute settlements** Storage reason: Act on the Consumer Protection in the Electronic Commerce Transactions, etc.  
Storage period: Three (3) years 

**\- History of website visits** Storage reason: Protection of Communications Secrets Act  
Storage period: Three (3) months 

### 6\. Procedure and Methods of Personal Information Destruction

The Company deletes personal information immediately after the purpose of its use has been achieved. The destruction procedure and methods are as follows.

#### A. Destruction procedure

  * -Information that a user inserts when subscribing to a service is relocated to a separate database (a separate file for paper documents) after the purpose of its use has been achieved. The information is stored in that location for a legally permitted period of time for specific purposes (refer to "Retention and Use Term") before being deleted.
  * -The personal information stated above is not used for other purposes, unless required by law.

#### B. Destruction method

  * -Personal information printed on paper is destroyed with a paper shredder or incinerator.
  * -Personal information stored in electronic files is deleted using technical methods that prevent its restoration.

### 7\. Rights of Users and Exercising Those Rights

  * -The user can view and modify his/her registered personal information at any time. In the event the user does not agree with the Company’s treatment of personal information, the user may refuse to approve to the Company’s handling of the personal information or request for a subscription cancellation (withdrawal). However, the user may have difficulties using portions of, or the whole service in such an event.
  * -Click [My Settings] to view or modify personal information of the user; to withdraw his/her membership (withdraw consent), the user must click [Delete Account] and directly view, modify information and cancel his/her membership.
  * -Or contact the chief privacy officer via written document, phone or email, and immediate measures will be enforced.
  * -If a user requests for correction of his/her personal information, the user cannot use or access his/her information until the correction is completed. If a user’s incorrect personal information has already been provided to a third party, the corrections made will be notified immediately to the third party, so that necessary corrections are made.
  * -The company processes personal information that has been deleted at the user’s request or at the request of a legal representative according to the terms and conditions described in "5. Personal Information Retention and Use Term", and imposes necessary measures to prevent the information from being viewed or used for other purposes.

### 8\. Installation/Management and Rejection of Automated Collection of Personal Information

#### A. What is a "cookie"?

  * -For the purpose of providing a personalized and customized service, the company uses a "cookie" to store and retrieve user’s information as needed.
  * -A cookie is a very small text file that is sent from the server that is used to operate the website to the user’s browser, and is saved in the hard disk of the user’s computer. When the user visits the website at a later date, the website server reads the contents of the cookie that is saved in the user’s hard disk to maintain the user’s environment setting and provide customized service to the user. 
  * -A cookie does not automatically or actively collect information that can be used to identify an individual. A user can always refuse to save these cookies or delete the cookies.

#### B. Company’s use of cookies

The company uses cookies to analyze the user’s visiting or use pattern of the Grafolio service, popular search keywords and user volume to provide an optimized and customized service that includes advertisement to users.

#### C. Installing/managing/rejecting cookies

  * -The user has the right to decide whether or not to install cookies. The user can use the option setting in the web browser to either allow all cookies, check every time a cookie is saved, or refuse to save all cookies.
  * -However, if the user decides not to save the cookies, he/she may have difficulties using some Grafolio services that require the user to login.
  * -How to set whether to allow cookies installation (For Internet Explorer users). 
    * ①Go to the [Tools] menu and select [Internet Option]
    * ②Click the [Privacy] tab.
    * ③Set the privacy level.

### 9\. Technical/Administrative Protective Measure for Personal Information

The company has come up with the following technical/administrative measures to ensure that is safely secured, and not lost, stolen, leaked, altered or damaged when processed.

#### A. Encrypting passwords

Grafolio member’s usernames are encrypted when saved and managed so that it can only be verified by the user. Personal information can only be viewed and changed by the user who knows the password.

#### B. Countermeasures against hacking attempts

The company is making its utmost efforts to prevent member’s personal information from being leaked or damaged due to hacking attempts or computer viruses.  
The company is backing up resources regularly to prepare for any possible damages made in the personal information, and is uses the latest vaccine programs to prevent user’s personal information or resources from being leaked or damaged. The company is also using methods, such as encrypted communication, to safely transmit personal information over the network.  
The company also uses a firewall system to control all unauthorized access from the outside, while making efforts to prepare all possible technical measures to secure security in the systems.

#### C. Minimizing employees who access the information and provide training

The right to handle personal information is limited to the employee in charge. A separate password is granted for this purpose and renewed at a regular basis. The employee in charge undergoes regular training to emphasize the importance of abiding by Grafolio Privacy Policy.

#### D. Operating an exclusive organization for privacy protection

The company operates an exclusive organization for privacy protection to confirm that the Grafolio Privacy Policy is being executed properly and to verify whether the employee in charge is abiding by the policy. Efforts are also made to immediately correct any issues upon detection of such problems.  
However, the company will not be responsible for any problems that arise from personal information, such as IDs or password, which is leaked due to the user’s negligence or problems in the internet.

### 10\. Contacting the Chief Privacy Officer and Personal Information Manager

You may file all privacy-related complaints, which arise during the use of the service, to the chief privacy officer or related department. The company will provide you with an immediate and sufficient response to your inquiry.

**Chief Privacy Officer** Name : _Jinkyu Lee_  
Email : [for inquiries](https://help.naver.com/support/mail/popup/mailInquiry.help?serviceNo=1074&categoryNo=15743)

**Personal Information Manager** Name : _Jaelim Lee_  
Email : [for inquiries](https://help.naver.com/support/mail/popup/mailInquiry.help?serviceNo=1074&categoryNo=15743)

Contact the organizations shown below to file reports or seek consultation for other privacy infringements;  
\- Privacy Infringement Report Center (www.118.or.kr )  
\- Cyber Crime Investigation Unit, Supreme Prosecutor’s Office (www.spo.go.kr)  
\- Cyber Terror Response Center, National Police Agency ( www.ctrc.go.kr) 

### 11\. Application

The "Grafolio Privacy Policy" does not apply to any collection of personal information that is conducted in websites that are linked to the Grafolio service.

### 12\. Notice (Notification) obligations

Any addition, change, or deletion to the current Privacy Policy will be notified 7 days in advance as a ‘Notification’ on the website or through ‘email’. However, important changes to user’s rights such as changes to collection or use of personal information or provision of information to third parties shall be notified 30 days in advance. 

\- Announcement Date: December 22th, 2016  
\- Enforcement Date: January 5th, 2017 

###  This Privacy Policy is originally written in Korean and this is a translated version thereof. Should there be a discordance between the Korean and English version, the Korean Privacy Policy shall be primarily applied.
